Hello and welcome to my talk about retrieval augmentation. My name is Joel Rorseth and I'm
안녕하세요. 검색 확대에 대한 강연에 오신 것을 환영합니다. 내 이름은 Joel Rorseth이고
a computer science student at the University of Waterloo. Today I'll be presenting two papers
워털루 대학교의 컴퓨터 과학 학생입니다. 오늘은 두 편의 논문을 발표하겠습니다.
about retrieval augmented generation as part of the Winter 2024 course CS886, Recent Advances
2024년 겨울 과정 CS886, 최근 발전의 일부인 검색 증강 세대에 대해
and Foundation Models, instructed by Dr. Wenhu Chen. Without further ado, let's get to it.
Wenhu Chen 박사가 지도한 기초 모델. 더 이상 고민하지 말고 시작해 보겠습니다.
The common theme about these two papers I'll be presenting is their approach to retrieval
내가 제시할 이 두 논문의 공통 주제는 검색에 대한 접근 방식입니다.
augmentation, which is they try to jointly fine-tune a retriever and language model.
증강, 즉 그들은 검색기와 언어 모델을 공동으로 미세 조정하려고 시도합니다.
Going in chronological order, the first paper we'll present is retrieval augmented generation
시간순으로 살펴보면 첫 번째로 소개할 논문은 검색증강세대(Retrieval Augmented Generation)이다.
for knowledge-intensive NLP tasks, published in 2020. Let's review some key terminology. The authors
지식 집약적인 NLP 작업용으로 2020년에 출판되었습니다. 몇 가지 주요 용어를 검토해 보겠습니다. 저자
refer to knowledge-intensive tasks, which are those that require external knowledge in order to do.
지식 집약적인 작업을 말하며, 이를 수행하기 위해 외부 지식이 필요한 작업을 말합니다.
The authors also refer to parametric and non-parametric memory. Parametric memory means
저자는 또한 파라메트릭 메모리와 비파라메트릭 메모리를 언급합니다. 파라메트릭 메모리는
knowledge that is stored in models and pre-trained weights. Non-parametric memory refers to knowledge
모델과 사전 훈련된 가중치에 저장된 지식입니다. 비모수적 기억은 지식을 의미합니다
that is stored in databases, retrieval systems, otherwise external. Hybrid memory are approaches
데이터베이스, 검색 시스템, 그렇지 않으면 외부에 저장됩니다. 하이브리드 메모리는 접근 방식입니다
that combine parametric and non-parametric, such as realm. In this paper, the authors are motivated
영역과 같이 매개변수와 비모수를 결합합니다. 이 논문에서 저자들은 동기를 부여받았다.
to propose a hybrid approach, specifically for sequence-to-sequence models. They note several
특히 시퀀스 간 모델에 대한 하이브리드 접근 방식을 제안합니다. 그들은 여러 가지를 지적합니다.
weaknesses of parametric memory, such as the fact that it's difficult to update or expand,
업데이트나 확장이 어렵다는 파라메트릭 메모리의 약점,
it can't be inspected directly, and of course, as we know, with their use in language models,
직접 검사할 수는 없으며 물론 우리가 알고 있듯이 언어 모델에서 사용하면
it can lead to hallucinations. On the other hand, non-parametric memory doesn't have these issues.
환각으로 이어질 수 있습니다. 반면, 비모수적 메모리에는 이러한 문제가 없습니다.
Non-parametric knowledge is easy to update or expand, and we can inspect it directly.
비모수적 지식은 업데이트하거나 확장하기 쉽고 직접 검사할 수 있습니다.
At least at the time of this writing, hybrid approaches were somewhat limited,
적어도 이 글을 쓰는 시점에는 하이브리드 접근 방식이 다소 제한되어 있었습니다.
they had only explored open-domain extractive QA, and hadn't yet been adapted for sequence-to-sequence
그들은 개방형 도메인 추출 QA만 탐색했으며 아직 시퀀스 간 QA에 적용되지 않았습니다.
models, hence the motivation to develop a specific hybrid approach for sequence-to-sequence models.
따라서 시퀀스 간 모델에 대한 특정 하이브리드 접근 방식을 개발하려는 동기가 부여됩니다.
The solution that the authors propose is a fine-tuning strategy named retrieval augmented
저자가 제안하는 솔루션은 Retrieval Augmented라는 미세 조정 전략입니다.
generation, RAG for short. Their architecture consists of three components, a pre-trained
세대, 줄여서 RAG. 그들의 아키텍처는 사전 훈련된 세 가지 구성 요소로 구성됩니다.
sequence-to-sequence transformer, which they use BART, a pre-trained neural retriever, in which they
사전 훈련된 신경 검색기인 BART를 사용하는 시퀀스-시퀀스 변환기.
use dense passage retriever, DPR, and a dense vector index, in this case, they've indexed Wikipedia.
밀집 통로 검색기, DPR 및 밀집 벡터 인덱스를 사용합니다. 이 경우에는 Wikipedia를 색인화했습니다.
There is an assumption that these models have already been trained enough so that they have
이러한 모델은 이미 충분히 학습되어 다음과 같은 결과를 얻을 수 있다고 가정합니다.
the ability to access knowledge. The RAG architecture boils down to two main components,
지식에 접근하는 능력. RAG 아키텍처는 두 가지 주요 구성 요소로 요약됩니다.
the retriever, which is the non-parametric memory, and the generator, which is the parametric.
비모수적 메모리인 검색기(Retriever)와 매개변수적 메모리인 생성자(Generator)입니다.
Here we have mathematical definitions of the probability distributions for each.
여기에 각각의 확률 분포에 대한 수학적 정의가 있습니다.
The retriever, p sub eta, gives the top k truncated distribution over potentially predicted
검색기 p sub eta는 잠재적으로 예측된 ​​상위 k개의 잘린 분포를 제공합니다.
text passages, z, given the query x. The generator, on the other hand, p sub theta,
쿼리 x가 주어지면 텍스트 구절 z. 반면에 생성기는 p sub theta,
gives the probability for the next token predicted, given previous tokens, the query x,
이전 토큰, 쿼리 x가 주어지면 예측된 다음 토큰에 대한 확률을 제공합니다.
and passage retrieved by the retriever, z. The authors actually propose two variants of their
그리고 리트리버에 의해 검색된 통로, z. 저자는 실제로 두 가지 변형을 제안합니다.
RAG model, RAG sequence and RAG token. With RAG sequence, they retrieve one document up front
RAG 모델, RAG 시퀀스 및 RAG 토큰. RAG 시퀀스를 사용하면 하나의 문서를 먼저 검색합니다.
and use that to generate the entire sequence. With RAG token, they use potentially a different
이를 사용하여 전체 시퀀스를 생성합니다. RAG 토큰을 사용하면 잠재적으로 다른 토큰을 사용합니다.
document to generate each token in the final sequence. Here we have the mathematical distributions
최종 시퀀스에서 각 토큰을 생성하는 문서입니다. 여기에 수학적 분포가 있습니다.
for each of these two generator variants. In the case of RAG sequence, we see that we
이 두 가지 생성기 변형 각각에 대해. RAG 시퀀스의 경우,
marginalize these probabilities over each of the top k documents. So for each top k document in
상위 k개 문서 각각에 대해 이러한 확률을 무시합니다. 따라서 각 상위 k 문서에 대해
isolation, we generate a probability for the entire output sequence. But then in the case of RAG
격리를 통해 전체 출력 시퀀스에 대한 확률을 생성합니다. 하지만 RAG의 경우에는
token, we see that this product moves to the beginning of the equation, which means that now,
토큰을 사용하면 이 곱이 방정식의 시작 부분으로 이동하는 것을 볼 수 있습니다. 즉, 이제
for each token, we can marginalize over each of these top k documents and just generate the
각 토큰에 대해 우리는 이러한 상위 k개 문서 각각을 소외시키고 다음을 생성할 수 있습니다.
distribution for the next output token one at a time. So let's discuss the implementation,
다음 출력 토큰을 한 번에 하나씩 배포합니다. 그럼 구현에 대해 논의해 보겠습니다.
starting with the encoding. The retriever is DPR, as mentioned earlier, which under the hood
인코딩부터 시작합니다. 리트리버는 앞서 언급한 것처럼 DPR입니다.
uses BERT to encode query and document. Then the similarity between those two is computed
BERT를 사용하여 쿼리와 문서를 인코딩합니다. 그런 다음 이 둘 사이의 유사성이 계산됩니다.
using maximum inner product search, MIPS. The generator is just a BERT large model,
최대 내적 탐색, MIPS를 사용합니다. 발전기는 그냥 BERT 대형 모델이고,
which has 400 million parameters. The input query and retrieved document are simply concatenated,
4억 개의 매개변수가 있습니다. 입력된 쿼리와 검색된 문서는 단순히 연결되어 있으며,
nothing fancy like some of the newer RAG and prompt engineering techniques of today.
오늘날의 최신 RAG 및 신속한 엔지니어링 기술만큼 멋진 것은 없습니다.
The decoding, which is how we determine the next token, is a little bit more nuanced. In the case
다음 토큰을 결정하는 방법인 디코딩은 조금 더 미묘합니다. 경우에
of RAG token, we can just plug this probability distribution into a standard beam decoder. But
RAG 토큰을 사용하면 이 확률 분포를 표준 빔 디코더에 연결할 수 있습니다. 하지만
in the case of RAG sequence, it doesn't really break into a per token likelihood. So we can't
RAG 시퀀스의 경우 실제로 토큰별 가능성으로 나뉘지 않습니다. 그래서 우리는 할 수 없습니다
just run a single beam search while the authors propose just to run a beam search for each of
저자는 각각에 대해 빔 검색을 실행하도록 제안하는 반면 단일 빔 검색을 실행하십시오.
the documents that are retrieved. The fine tuning implementation is relatively
검색된 문서. 미세 조정 구현은 상대적으로
straightforward. They jointly fine tune both the retriever and the generator. Specifically,
똑바로. 그들은 리트리버와 생성기를 공동으로 미세 조정합니다. 구체적으로,
they update the retriever query encoder and the generator, but they don't update the retriever's
검색기 쿼리 인코더와 생성기는 업데이트하지만 검색기의 쿼리 인코더는 업데이트하지 않습니다.
document encoder. This is simply because they didn't find it necessary to achieve strong
문서 인코더. 이는 단순히 강한 목표를 달성하는 것이 필요하지 않다고 생각했기 때문입니다.
performance, and because it's relatively expensive. The fine tuning data that they use
성능도 좋고 가격도 상대적으로 비싸기 때문이죠. 그들이 사용하는 미세 조정 데이터
are a collection of pairs x and y, which will be defined in the experiment section.
는 실험 섹션에서 정의될 x와 y 쌍의 모음입니다.
The objective function is a simple minimization of a negative log probability done using stochastic
목적 함수는 확률론을 사용하여 수행된 음의 로그 확률을 간단히 최소화하는 것입니다.
gradient descent and the atom optimizer. Here we have a nice diagram to summarize things visually.
경사하강법과 원자 최적화 프로그램. 여기에 내용을 시각적으로 요약하는 멋진 다이어그램이 있습니다.
We can see that the retriever flows into the generator, and then we back propagate through
검색기가 생성기로 흘러 들어간 다음 다시 전파되는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
the generator and the retriever's query encoder queue in this diagram.
이 다이어그램의 생성기와 검색기의 쿼리 인코더 큐.
So let's move on to discussing the experiment and talk about first the retrieval setup.
이제 실험에 대한 논의로 넘어가서 먼저 검색 설정에 대해 이야기해 보겠습니다.
The authors use the Wikipedia dump from December 2018, and after using 100 word chunks,
저자는 2018년 12월의 Wikipedia 덤프를 사용하고, 100개의 단어 청크를 사용한 후,
they have 21 million documents that they choose to index. The index process itself is pretty
그들은 색인을 생성하기로 선택한 문서가 2,100만 개 있습니다. 인덱스 프로세스 자체가 예쁘네요
straightforward. They use a BERT model to encode each of the documents, and that gives them embeddings.
똑바로. 그들은 BERT 모델을 사용하여 각 문서를 인코딩하고 이를 통해 임베딩을 제공합니다.
The embeddings are inserted into a MIPS index using FICE. They also use hierarchical navigable
임베딩은 FICE를 사용하여 MIPS 인덱스에 삽입됩니다. 또한 계층적 탐색 가능을 사용합니다.
small world for faster retrieval, and the retrieval itself, while during training,
더 빠른 검색을 위한 작은 세계와 검색 자체를 훈련하는 동안
they use either 5 or 10 documents for K, and during testing, they set K using the depth data.
K에는 5개 또는 10개의 문서를 사용하고 테스트 중에는 깊이 데이터를 사용하여 K를 설정합니다.
In the experiment, the authors test their method with four different tasks.
실험에서 저자는 네 가지 다른 작업을 통해 방법을 테스트합니다.
Open domain QA, abstractive QA, jeopardy question generation, and fact verification.
오픈 도메인 QA, 추상적인 QA, 위험 질문 생성 및 사실 확인.
Starting with the open domain QA task, of course, the objective with this is to task their method
물론 오픈 도메인 QA 작업부터 시작하여 목표는 자신의 방법을 작업하는 것입니다.
with answering objective factual questions. They actually have four different QA data sets that
객관적이고 사실적인 질문에 답하면서 그들은 실제로 4개의 서로 다른 QA 데이터 세트를 가지고 있습니다.
they're evaluating on separately. The setup is that they use each of these question answer
따로 평가하고 있어요. 설정은 이러한 각 질문 답변을 사용하는 것입니다.
pairs from these data sets in order to find two of the models, and the baselines they compare
두 가지 모델을 찾기 위해 이러한 데이터 세트에서 쌍을 찾고, 그들이 비교하는 기준선을 찾습니다.
against are open book models which have access to external knowledge and some closed book models
반대되는 것은 외부 지식에 접근할 수 있는 개방형 북 모델과 일부 폐쇄형 북 모델입니다.
that don't have any access to external knowledge. The metric used is exact match, meaning that
외부 지식에 접근할 수 없습니다. 사용된 측정항목은 정확히 일치합니다. 즉,
the answer generated has to be an exact match to the goal ground truth.
생성된 답변은 목표 실제값과 정확히 일치해야 합니다.
So RAG has quite strong performance on this QA task. You can see in the bottom two rows that RAG
따라서 RAG는 이 QA 작업에서 매우 강력한 성능을 발휘합니다. 아래 두 행에서 RAG가 표시된 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
token and RAG sequence improve on the closed and open book methods by quite a few points.
토큰 및 RAG 시퀀스는 비공개 및 공개 도서 방식을 상당히 향상시킵니다.
In the answer to why is quite simple. It's because RAG can generate answers regardless of
이유에 대한 대답은 매우 간단합니다. RAG는 ​​무엇이든 관계없이 답변을 생성할 수 있기 때문입니다.
whether or not the documents that it retrieves actually contain the answer. If the answer isn't
검색한 문서에 실제로 답변이 포함되어 있는지 여부. 대답이 그렇지 않다면
in the documents, then other documents can provide useful information that might even
문서에서 다른 문서는 유용한 정보를 제공할 수 있습니다.
lead to an answer. In general, RAG combines the best of both worlds. It can combine the benefits
답변으로 이어집니다. 일반적으로 RAG는 두 세계의 장점을 결합합니다. 장점을 결합할 수 있습니다.
of open and closed book, which is why we see an improvement in performance here.
열린 책과 닫힌 책의 차이로 인해 여기에서 성능이 향상되는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
Moving to task two, abstract of QA is the focus here, specifically natural language generation,
작업 2로 이동하면 QA 개요, 특히 자연어 생성에 중점을 두고 있습니다.
NLG. The data set they used to test this is MS Marko NLG task version 2.1,
NLG. 이를 테스트하는 데 사용한 데이터 세트는 MS Marko NLG 작업 버전 2.1입니다.
which is a large data set of questions, each having 10 gold search engine passages from
이는 질문의 대규모 데이터 세트로, 각 질문에는 10개의 골드 검색 엔진 구절이 있습니다.
which a full sentence answer is annotated. Then for the setup, they fine tune using
전체 문장 답변에 주석이 추가됩니다. 그런 다음 설정을 위해 다음을 사용하여 미세 조정합니다.
XY pairs that are question answer pairs. Specifically, they force RAG to rely on parametric
질문 답변 쌍인 XY 쌍입니다. 특히 RAG가 파라메트릭에 의존하도록 강제합니다.
knowledge more by ignoring these goal passages that are provided in the MS Marko data set.
MS Marko 데이터 세트에 제공되는 이러한 목표 구절을 무시하여 더 많은 지식을 얻을 수 있습니다.
The baselines they compare against are BART and the state of the art performance,
그들이 비교하는 기준은 BART와 최첨단 성능입니다.
and they use two different metrics, blue and rouge. For this NLG task, RAG actually approaches
파란색과 연지라는 두 가지 측정항목을 사용합니다. 이 NLG 작업을 위해 RAG는 실제로 접근합니다.
state of the art. And all of this is considering the fact that the state of the art approaches
최첨단. 그리고 이 모든 것은 최첨단 기술이 접근한다는 사실을 고려하고 있습니다.
have access to the goal passages, which are required in order to determine some answers.
몇 가지 답을 결정하는 데 필요한 목표 구절에 접근할 수 있습니다.
And not all the questions are answerable from just the Wikipedia data that RAG has access to
그리고 RAG가 액세스할 수 있는 Wikipedia 데이터만으로 모든 질문에 답할 수 있는 것은 아닙니다.
in these experiments. And nonetheless, we are approaching state of the art as indicated in the
이 실험에서는. 그럼에도 불구하고 우리는 다음과 같이 최첨단 기술에 접근하고 있습니다.
table here, and RAG is outperforming BART pretty consistently. The third task being evaluated
여기에 표가 있으며 RAG는 지속적으로 BART를 능가합니다. 평가 중인 세 번째 작업
is jeopardy question generation. So what is a jeopardy question? It's a factual statement
위험 질문 생성입니다. 그렇다면 위험 질문이란 무엇입니까? 사실에 근거한 진술입니다
that prompts an exact answer. An example is, in 1986, Mexico scored as the first country to host
정확한 답변을 요구하는 것입니다. 예를 들어, 1986년 멕시코는 최초로 개최국으로 기록되었습니다.
this international sports competition twice. The answer, of course, is the World Cup.
이번 국제 스포츠 대회는 두 번이나 진행됐다. 답은 당연히 월드컵이다.
The task here for the RAG model is to generate these jeopardy questions, condition on answer
RAG 모델의 임무는 답변을 조건으로 이러한 위험 질문을 생성하는 것입니다.
entities. So the fine tuning setup is actually flipped from the other QA settings. So from the
엔터티. 따라서 미세 조정 설정은 실제로 다른 QA 설정에서 반전됩니다. 그래서
answer, we're trying to predict the question. So we have answer question pairs. They use a search QA
대답, 우리는 질문을 예측하려고 노력하고 있습니다. 그래서 우리는 답변 질문 쌍을 가지고 있습니다. 검색 QA를 사용합니다.
data set, which is just a pretty general QA data set. The baseline method is BART once again,
데이터 세트는 꽤 일반적인 QA 데이터 세트입니다. 기본 방법은 다시 한번 BART입니다.
and they're using two metrics, blue and a different variant of blue. So we see that once again,
파란색과 파란색의 다른 변형이라는 두 가지 측정항목을 사용하고 있습니다. 그래서 우리는 그것을 다시 한 번 봅니다.
on this task, RAG is performing quite strongly. RAG token actually outperforms both RAG sequence
이 작업에서 RAG는 매우 강력한 성능을 발휘합니다. RAG 토큰은 실제로 두 RAG 시퀀스보다 성능이 뛰어납니다.
and BART. This is probably because RAG token can pull from multiple different documents.
그리고 바트. 이는 아마도 RAG 토큰이 여러 다른 문서에서 가져올 수 있기 때문일 것입니다.
And of course, both RAG approaches retain their advantage in being able to use both
물론 두 RAG 접근 방식 모두 두 가지를 모두 사용할 수 있다는 이점을 유지합니다.
the retriever and the generator to complete these questions. They actually run a separate
리트리버와 생성기가 이러한 질문을 완성합니다. 실제로는 별도로 운영하고 있는
experiment where they ask human evaluators to compare RAG and BART. And they found that the
인간 평가자에게 RAG와 BART를 비교하도록 요청하는 실험입니다. 그리고 그들은 다음과 같은 사실을 발견했습니다.
human evaluators prefer RAG. Specifically, they found that the generations are more factual and
인간 평가자는 RAG를 선호합니다. 특히, 그들은 세대가 더 사실적이고
they're more specific. The final task in these experiments is fact verification. And what this
그들은 더 구체적입니다. 이 실험의 마지막 과제는 사실 검증이다. 그리고 이건 뭐지
means is the model must classify whether a claim is true, false or unverifiable. They actually
이는 모델이 주장이 참인지, 거짓인지, 검증할 수 없는지 분류해야 함을 의미합니다. 그들은 실제로
have two different approaches that they test, a three-way and two-way classification. In the
테스트하는 두 가지 접근 방식, 즉 3방향 분류와 양방향 분류가 있습니다. 에서
case of three-way, the label or class as they refer to it can be either supports, refutes,
3방향의 경우, 그들이 참조하는 레이블이나 클래스는 지지, 반박,
or not enough info. The two-way classification is just supports or refutes. They use a data set
또는 정보가 충분하지 않습니다. 양방향 분류는 단지 지지 또는 반박일 뿐입니다. 그들은 데이터 세트를 사용합니다
called FEVER, which is a data set of claims and evidence annotations for these claims that uses
FEVER라고 불리는 이는 주장과 이러한 주장에 대한 증거 주석의 데이터 세트입니다.
Wikipedia data. They can construct fine-tuning samples using the claim and class pairs from
위키피디아 데이터. 그들은 다음의 클레임과 클래스 쌍을 사용하여 미세 조정 샘플을 구성할 수 있습니다.
this data. Each class is mapped to a unique output token. And then, similar to the natural
이 데이터. 각 클래스는 고유한 출력 토큰에 매핑됩니다. 그러면 자연과 비슷하게
language generation task, we simply ignore the evidence annotations to make the challenge a
언어 생성 작업에서 우리는 도전 과제를 만들기 위해 증거 주석을 무시합니다.
little bit more for RAG. They use two baselines, BART, and the state-of-the-art performance.
RAG에게는 조금 더. 그들은 BART와 최첨단 성능이라는 두 가지 기준을 사용합니다.
And the metric is just the label accuracy on this classification.
측정항목은 이 분류에 대한 라벨 정확도일 뿐입니다.
The RAG scores in this approach and the table on the left are actually quite good. They're
이 접근 방식의 RAG 점수와 왼쪽 표는 실제로 꽤 좋습니다. 그들은
approaching the state-of-the-art, not quite state-of-the-art, but only a couple points off.
최첨단에 접근하고 있지만 완전히 최첨단은 아니지만 몇 가지 지적 사항만 있습니다.
This is pretty impressive considering that the state-of-the-art methods do have access to that
최첨단 방법으로 접근할 수 있다는 점을 고려하면 이는 매우 인상적입니다.
gold evidence annotation from the FEVER data set and that these state-of-the-art methods use complex
FEVER 데이터 세트의 금 증거 주석과 이러한 최첨단 방법은 복잡한
pipelines that are trained with supervision. So nonetheless, RAG scores are approaching state-of-the-
감독을 통해 훈련된 파이프라인. 그럼에도 불구하고 RAG 점수는 최고 수준에 근접하고 있습니다.
art. The authors also make a note that there is high overlap between the RAG documents that are
미술. 저자는 또한 RAG 문서 사이에 중복되는 부분이 많다는 점을 지적했습니다.
retrieved and this gold evidence. So this concludes our discussion of the first paper.
이 금 증거물을 회수했습니다. 이로써 첫 번째 논문에 대한 논의가 끝났습니다.
Now we'll move on to the second paper called Replug. The full title of this paper is Replug,
이제 Replug라는 두 번째 문서로 넘어갑니다. 이 문서의 전체 제목은 Replug입니다.
Retrieval Augmented Black Box Language Models Published Very Recently in 2023.
2023년에 매우 최근에 발표된 증강 블랙박스 언어 모델 검색.
The key difference in this paper, as compared to the previous one and previous RAG papers,
이전 논문 및 이전 RAG 논문과 비교하여 본 논문의 주요 차이점은 다음과 같습니다.
is the focus on black box language models. The issue that they point out to motivate this paper
블랙박스 언어 모델에 중점을 두고 있습니다. 이 논문의 동기를 부여하기 위해 그들이 지적한 문제
is that fine-tuning language models with retrieval requires so-called white box access,
검색 기능을 갖춘 미세 조정 언어 모델에는 소위 화이트 박스 액세스가 필요하다는 것입니다.
which means we need access to the language model parameters in order to be able to fine-tune them.
이는 언어 모델 매개변수를 미세 조정하려면 해당 매개변수에 액세스해야 함을 의미합니다.
And in practice, many popular large language models, such as ChatGBT or Gemini, are only
그리고 실제로 ChatGBT나 Gemini와 같은 인기 있는 많은 대규모 언어 모델은
accessible via an API. So we can't get any of that sort of data. We certainly can't fine-tune or
API를 통해 액세스할 수 있습니다. 그래서 우리는 그런 종류의 데이터를 얻을 수 없습니다. 우리는 확실히 미세 조정을 할 수 없습니다.
access model parameters in a lot of cases. This is where Replug comes in. The focus of Replug
많은 경우 모델 매개변수에 액세스합니다. 이것이 바로 Replug가 등장하는 곳입니다. Replug의 초점
specifically is retrieval augmentation in the black box setting. Black box meaning that we
특히 블랙박스 설정에서 검색 기능이 강화됩니다. 블랙박스는 우리가
don't have any assumption of access to model parameters. So the language model specifically
모델 매개변수에 대한 액세스를 가정하지 않습니다. 따라서 언어 모델은 구체적으로
is a black box. The retriever could be a black box, but it's optionally tunable and they'll
블랙박스다. 리트리버는 블랙박스일 수도 있지만 선택적으로 조정 가능하며
discuss a variant of their method to address this potential trainability. But how does it work?
이러한 잠재적인 훈련 가능성을 해결하기 위한 다양한 방법을 논의합니다. 하지만 어떻게 작동하나요?
Well first, Replug gets documents from a retriever, it then pre-pens these documents to the
먼저 Replug는 검색기로부터 문서를 가져온 다음 이 문서를
original language model input, and then it feeds this to the language model.
원래 언어 모델을 입력한 다음 이를 언어 모델에 제공합니다.
Let's dive into the implementation of this architecture, starting with retrieval.
검색부터 시작하여 이 아키텍처의 구현을 살펴보겠습니다.
We're given a corpus of m documents, d, and an input context or query, x. The output of the
m개의 문서로 구성된 코퍼스 d와 입력 컨텍스트 또는 쿼리 x가 제공됩니다. 의 출력
retrieval model is the k documents in d that are most relevant to x, denoted as d prime.
검색 모델은 d 소수로 표시되는 x와 가장 관련성이 높은 d의 k 문서입니다.
We'll sometimes refer to this as the top k documents in d. So how do we determine these
우리는 때때로 이것을 d의 상위 k 문서라고 부를 것입니다. 그러면 우리는 이것을 어떻게 결정합니까?
documents? Well, we pre-compute an embedding for each document, d, when we construct a
서류? 음, 우리는 다음을 구성할 때 각 문서 d에 대한 임베딩을 미리 계산합니다.
FICE index, just like in the last paper. We encode the input x to obtain an embedding,
지난 논문에서와 마찬가지로 FICE 지수입니다. 임베딩을 얻기 위해 입력 x를 인코딩합니다.
then we simply find the top k most similar documents to x using a cosine similarity function,
그런 다음 코사인 유사성 함수를 사용하여 x와 가장 유사한 상위 k개 문서를 찾습니다.
denoted as s. When implementing the language model, or the generator as it was referred to
s로 표시됩니다. 언어 모델 또는 생성기를 구현할 때 참조된 대로
in the previous paper, there is a bit of a question. If you recall, we said that we were going to
이전 논문에 약간의 질문이 있었습니다. 기억나시면 우리가 가겠다고 했잖아요.
pre-pend these k documents to the input text x. But the real question is, will all of these k
이 k개 문서를 입력 텍스트 x 앞에 추가합니다. 하지만 진짜 질문은, 이 모든 k가 과연 그럴 것인가 하는 것입니다.
documents fit? Let's define a bit of terminology here. The context window is the input text for
서류가 맞나요? 여기서 약간의 용어를 정의해 보겠습니다. 컨텍스트 창은 다음에 대한 입력 텍스트입니다.
language model, and the size of this context window is the number of tokens that can fit in it.
언어 모델이며 이 컨텍스트 창의 크기는 그 안에 들어갈 수 있는 토큰의 수입니다.
But the problem is that the context window, which is a fixed size, may not fit k documents.
그런데 문제는 고정된 크기의 컨텍스트 창이 k개의 문서에 맞지 않을 수 있다는 것입니다.
The context size varies by language model. The size of each document could vary,
컨텍스트 크기는 언어 모델에 따라 다릅니다. 각 문서의 크기는 다를 수 있으며,
and the number of retrieved documents, k itself, could certainly vary. So we don't really know.
검색된 문서의 수 k 자체는 확실히 다를 수 있습니다. 그래서 우리는 정말로 모릅니다.
To address this uncertainty, the authors propose a solution that they call
이러한 불확실성을 해결하기 위해 저자는 다음과 같은 솔루션을 제안합니다.
ensemble inference scheme. The idea is quite simple. Let's just do k separate language model
앙상블 추론 방식. 아이디어는 아주 간단합니다. k개의 별도 언어 모델을 수행해 보겠습니다.
predictions, and then bring them back together at the end. So specifically, we'll concatenate each
예측을 한 다음 마지막에 다시 합칩니다. 구체적으로 각 항목을 연결해 보겠습니다.
of those top k documents, d with x. And then once we have k concatenations, we'll make a separate
상위 k개 문서 중 d는 x입니다. 그런 다음 k개의 연결이 있으면 별도의
inference call for each, and simply ensemble all of their output probabilities. The benefits, of
각각에 대해 추론을 호출하고 모든 출력 확률을 간단히 앙상블합니다. 이점은
course, are that the inference calls can be parallelized. And the authors argue that there's
물론 추론 호출을 병렬화할 수 있다는 것입니다. 그리고 저자들은 다음과 같이 주장합니다.
minimal overhead compared to a single inference that contains all k documents. The language models,
k개의 문서를 모두 포함하는 단일 추론에 비해 오버헤드가 최소화됩니다. 언어 모델,
context window only needs to be large enough in order to fit x and the largest of the k documents.
컨텍스트 창은 x와 k개의 문서 중 가장 큰 문서에 맞도록 충분히 커야 합니다.
At the bottom here, we have a mathematical definition for the probability distribution,
여기 하단에는 확률 분포에 대한 수학적 정의가 있습니다.
which is simply a product of the generator using the concatenation of d and x,
이는 단순히 d와 x의 연결을 사용하는 생성기의 곱입니다.
multiplied by a similarity function between d and x, which is supposed to represent the retriever here.
여기에 검색자를 나타내는 것으로 추정되는 d와 x 사이의 유사성 함수를 곱합니다.
As mentioned earlier, replug can optionally fine tune a retriever, in which case their variant
앞서 언급했듯이 replug는 선택적으로 검색기를 미세 조정할 수 있으며, 이 경우 변형이 가능합니다.
is known as replug lsr. Language models supervise retrieval. The idea behind this
replug lsr로 알려져 있습니다. 언어 모델은 검색을 감독합니다. 이것 뒤에 숨어있는 아이디어
optimization is to train the retriever to find documents that minimize the language model's
최적화는 언어 모델의 오류를 최소화하는 문서를 찾도록 검색기를 훈련시키는 것입니다.
perplexity. They have a couple steps for this. It starts by retrieving the top k documents,
당황. 이에 대한 몇 가지 단계가 있습니다. 상위 k개 문서를 검색하는 것으로 시작합니다.
d prime. Then we compute the retrieval likelihood of each of those documents. It's a simple softmax
d 소수. 그런 다음 각 문서의 검색 가능성을 계산합니다. 간단한 소프트맥스입니다
function that uses the similarity between that document and x. We then compute the language
해당 문서와 x 간의 유사성을 사용하는 함수입니다. 그런 다음 언어를 계산합니다.
model's likelihood of each document using ground truth from the training data set.
훈련 데이터 세트의 실제 정보를 사용하여 각 문서의 모델 가능성.
This is a simple softmax function, very similar in terms of the probabilities from the language
이것은 언어의 확률 측면에서 매우 유사한 간단한 소프트맥스 함수입니다.
model. Finally, we minimize the KL divergence between these two probability distributions
모델. 마지막으로, 이 두 확률 분포 사이의 KL 차이를 최소화합니다.
in order to jointly align them. The training implementation in this paper is, of course,
공동으로 정렬하기 위해. 물론 이 문서의 교육 구현은 다음과 같습니다.
much simpler than the last paper, since they're doing less fine tuning. The regular replug approach
미세 조정 작업을 덜 수행하기 때문에 지난 논문보다 훨씬 간단합니다. 일반적인 재플러그 방식
doesn't call for any fine tuning, so we can use an off-the-shelf retriever model and off-the-shelf
미세 조정이 필요하지 않으므로 기성품 검색 모델과 기성품을 사용할 수 있습니다.
language model. In this paper, they're using contriver or contriever and GPT-3 curry for the
언어 모델. 이 논문에서는 Contriver 또는 Contriever와 GPT-3 카레를 사용하고 있습니다.
language model. For replug lsr, they're sampling training queries from the pile dataset, which
언어 모델. lsr을 다시 연결하기 위해 더미 데이터세트에서 훈련 쿼리를 샘플링합니다.
is a very large dataset of scraped text. Each of these is 256 tokens and they have 800,000 sequences.
스크랩된 텍스트로 구성된 매우 큰 데이터 세트입니다. 이들 각각은 256개의 토큰이며 800,000개의 시퀀스를 갖습니다.
The queries are split into input context, x, and ground truth continuation, y. Each of these are
쿼리는 입력 컨텍스트 x와 실제 연속 y로 분할됩니다. 이들 각각은
128 tokens, and these x, y pairs become the basis of our fine tuning dataset. For the retriever,
128개 토큰, 이 x, y 쌍은 미세 조정 데이터 세트의 기초가 됩니다. 리트리버의 경우,
we sample external documents from the pile, the same dataset. Each of these will be 128 tokens,
동일한 데이터 세트인 더미에서 외부 문서를 샘플링합니다. 각각은 128개의 토큰이 됩니다.
resulting in 36 million documents. The authors do note that they check for overlapping queries
결과적으로 3,600만 개의 문서가 생성되었습니다. 저자는 중복되는 쿼리를 확인한다는 점에 유의합니다.
and documents, and verify that there are no overlapping queries and documents.
및 문서를 확인하고, 중복되는 쿼리와 문서가 없는지 확인합니다.
Once again, we have a nice diagram to put everything together and summarize things visually.
다시 한 번, 모든 것을 하나로 모으고 시각적으로 요약할 수 있는 멋진 다이어그램이 있습니다.
In the bottom left, we can see a test context, x, which is an example of a query being asked,
왼쪽 하단에는 요청되는 쿼리의 예인 테스트 컨텍스트 x가 표시됩니다.
in this case, Jobs is the CEO of Blank. The answer, of course, is Apple, and we can see that the
이 경우 잡스는 블랭크의 CEO이다. 물론 대답은 Apple입니다.
retriever finds a couple of documents that are related to Steve Jobs and Apple, and then feeds
검색자는 Steve Jobs 및 Apple과 관련된 문서 몇 개를 찾은 다음 피드를 제공합니다.
the test context, x, and each of these documents, d, into a black box language model.
테스트 컨텍스트 x와 이러한 각 문서 d를 블랙박스 언어 모델로 변환합니다.
Then on the right, we see the ensemble approach, where each of these documents
그런 다음 오른쪽에는 앙상블 접근 방식이 표시됩니다.
is paired with the test context, x, and then fed to a language model.
테스트 컨텍스트 x와 쌍을 이루고 언어 모델에 제공됩니다.
Then these output probabilities are ensemble together to get an answer of Apple.
그런 다음 이러한 출력 확률을 함께 앙상블하여 Apple의 답변을 얻습니다.
Moving now to the experiment section, the authors have three tasks in this paper that
이제 실험 섹션으로 이동하면 저자는 이 논문에서 세 가지 작업을 수행합니다.
they're evaluating their approach with. The first is general language modeling,
그들은 그들의 접근 방식을 평가하고 있습니다. 첫 번째는 일반 언어 모델링이며,
followed by their performance on massive multitask language understanding,
대규모 멀티태스킹 언어 이해에 대한 성과가 이어졌습니다.
MMLU for short. This is followed with the open domain question answering task,
줄여서 MMLU. 그 다음에는 오픈 도메인 질문 답변 작업이 이어집니다.
similar to the previous paper. In this first task, the authors are trying to understand
이전 논문과 비슷하다. 이 첫 번째 작업에서 저자는 이해하려고 노력하고 있습니다.
how Replug improves language modeling in language models. So the metric they're
Replug가 언어 모델의 언어 모델링을 개선하는 방법. 그래서 그들이 측정하는 것은
using to evaluate this is known as bits per byte, which is a very popular metric to gauge
이를 평가하는 데 사용되는 것은 바이트당 비트수로 알려져 있으며 측정하는 데 매우 널리 사용되는 측정항목입니다.
language modeling performance. They're using the pile dataset once again, and for the setup,
언어 모델링 성능. 그들은 파일 데이터세트를 다시 한 번 사용하고 있으며 설정을 위해
Replug will use 128 token context windows. The retrieval corpus is 367 million documents,
Replug는 128개의 토큰 컨텍스트 창을 사용합니다. 검색 코퍼스는 3억 6,700만 개의 문서이며,
each of them being 128 tokens that are sampled from the pile. The retriever will then retrieve
각각은 더미에서 샘플링된 128개의 토큰입니다. 그러면 리트리버가 검색합니다.
the top 10 documents. The specific baselines what we're going to integrate Replug into are a number
상위 10개 문서. Replug를 통합할 구체적인 기준은 다음과 같습니다.
of GPT two models and a number of GPT three models spanning various different sizes.
GPT 2가지 모델과 다양한 크기에 걸친 다수의 GPT 3가지 모델이 있습니다.
For each of these models, we see that adding Replug consistently shows improvement for this
이러한 각 모델에 대해 Replug를 추가하면 지속적으로 개선되는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
language modeling task. Highlighted in blue, we have gain percentage columns showing that by adding
언어 모델링 작업. 파란색으로 강조 표시된 부분에는 다음을 추가하면 얻을 수 있는 이득 비율 열이 있습니다.
regular Replug with no fine tuning, we can gain anywhere from about three to six percent improvement.
미세 조정 없이 정기적으로 다시 연결하면 약 3~6% 정도 성능이 향상될 수 있습니다.
And then by adding Replug LSR, we gain anywhere from six to nine percent improvement on the
그런 다음 Replug LSR을 추가하면 성능이 6~9% 향상됩니다.
language modeling task, which is quite impressive. In this second task, the authors are interested
꽤 인상적인 언어 모델링 작업입니다. 이 두 번째 작업에 저자가 관심을 갖고 있습니다.
in understanding whether Replug has performance benefits for the MMLU benchmark. MMLU, which
Replug가 MMLU 벤치마크에 대한 성능 이점을 가지고 있는지 이해합니다. MMLU는
once again stands for Massive Multitask Language Understanding, is a dataset of multiple choice
다시 한번 Massive Multitask Language Understanding의 약자이며 객관식 데이터 세트입니다.
questions. These questions span 57 different tasks and four different categories,
질문. 이 질문은 57가지 작업과 4가지 카테고리에 걸쳐 있습니다.
humanities, STEM, social sciences, and other. In this setup, they're using Codex, a language model,
인문학, STEM, 사회과학 등. 이 설정에서는 언어 모델인 Codex를 사용하고 있습니다.
and adding Replug to that and evaluating everything in a five shot setting.
여기에 Replug를 추가하고 5회 설정에서 모든 것을 평가합니다.
For each of the MMLU test queries, we retrieve and prepend 10 k equals 10 Wikipedia documents
각 MMLU 테스트 쿼리에 대해 10k를 검색하여 10개의 Wikipedia 문서와 동일하게 앞에 추가합니다.
from the December 2018 dump, and then we ensemble the output. The baselines in this comparison are
2018년 12월 덤프에서 추출한 다음 출력을 앙상블합니다. 이 비교의 기준은 다음과 같습니다.
language models that are state-of-the-art for MMLU, which include Codex, Palm, and Flan Palm,
Codex, Palm, Flan Palm 등 MMLU를 위한 최첨단 언어 모델,
as well as RAG LLM approaches, Atlas in particular. The metric for this particular task
RAG LLM 접근 방식, 특히 Atlas도 마찬가지입니다. 이 특정 작업에 대한 측정항목
is simply the accuracy of these questions. In these results, we see consistent improvement
단순히 이러한 질문의 정확성입니다. 이 결과에서 우리는 지속적인 개선을 확인했습니다
of Codex simply by integrating Replug. In the top row highlighted in blue, we see the performance
Replug를 통합하여 간단히 Codex를 사용할 수 있습니다. 파란색으로 강조 표시된 맨 위 행에는 성능이 표시됩니다.
of Codex on its own. And then the bottom two rows highlighted in blue, we see Codex with Replug
Codex 자체적으로. 그런 다음 파란색으로 강조 표시된 맨 아래 두 행에 Replug 기능이 있는 Codex가 표시됩니다.
integrated. The difference between Replug and Replug LSR being integrated is somewhat negligible,
통합. 통합되는 Replug와 Replug LSR의 차이는 다소 미미합니다.
but generally by integrating Replug, we can improve the performance of Codex by several points.
그러나 일반적으로 Replug를 통합하면 Codex의 성능을 여러 지점으로 향상시킬 수 있습니다.
In this final task, the authors are testing open domain question answering,
이 마지막 작업에서 저자는 오픈 도메인 질문 답변을 테스트하고 있습니다.
just like in the last paper. So the task is again answering objective factual questions.
지난번 논문처럼요. 따라서 과제는 다시 객관적이고 사실적인 질문에 답하는 것입니다.
This time, they're only looking at two datasets, natural questions, and trivia QB.
이번에는 자연 질문과 퀴즈 QB라는 두 가지 데이터 세트만 보고 있습니다.
The setup is quite similar to the previous task. They're using the Codex language model
설정은 이전 작업과 매우 유사합니다. Codex 언어 모델을 사용하고 있습니다.
and integrating Replug and evaluating this in a 16-shot setting. They're using Wikipedia for
Replug를 통합하고 이를 16샷 설정에서 평가합니다. 그들은 Wikipedia를 다음 용도로 사용하고 있습니다.
retrieval and retrieving the top 10 documents. For baselines, they're using Chinchilla, Palm,
상위 10개 문서를 검색하고 검색합니다. 기준으로는 Chinchilla, Palm,
and just plain Codex. And they're using a couple RAG LLM approaches, such as Retro, R2D2, and Atlas.
그리고 그냥 평범한 코덱스. 그리고 Retro, R2D2, Atlas와 같은 몇 가지 RAG LLM 접근 방식을 사용하고 있습니다.
Once again, we see that by integrating Replug into Codex, we can gain substantial performance
다시 한 번 Replug를 Codex에 통합하면 상당한 성능을 얻을 수 있음을 알 수 있습니다.
improvements, about four to five points here. Compared to plain language models and even
개선 사항은 대략 4~5점 정도입니다. 일반 언어 모델과 비교했을 때 심지어
other RAG enabled models, we see that Codex and Replug beats them all, at least in the
다른 RAG 지원 모델의 경우 Codex와 Replug가 적어도 부문에서는 모든 모델을 능가한다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
few-shot setting which is being evaluated here. This concludes my presentation about these two
여기에서 평가되고 있는 몇 장의 설정입니다. 이것으로 이 두 가지에 대한 발표를 마치겠습니다.
retrieval augmented generation papers. Thanks for your attention. If you have any questions,
증강세대 논문 검색. 주목 해 주셔서 감사합니다. 만약 질문이 있다면,
feel free to reach out at the email on screen.
화면에 표시된 이메일로 언제든지 문의해 주세요.